hmm
today's just one of those days where i
just don't know how to start the video
well welcome back to another episode of
hermitcraft today we are of course going
to be tackling
the same beast that we have done for the
last couple of episodes the interior of
the mansion and i've been looking at
some feedback from all of you guys and
it would seem
that everyone is on the same page that
this is looking good and it looks like
you guys are just as surprised as i am
that i'm even doing this interior in the
first place so i think we can all be
proud of ourselves so what are we going
to be doing in here today well this
build has been taking me quite a long
time so i'm taking it bit by bit and
today i want to be adding as you
probably know from the the thumbnail of
this video is i want to be adding a
giant chandelier right there
nice and bright and full of diamonds and
also i want to add myself a fancy floor
now this floor
was actually kind of inspired by cub fan
over his base he made a really really
nice looking floor in fact let's let's
go there now and have a look so you can
see where the inspiration came from aha
the the mega pyramid of cub fan look at
the size of this thing okay so
let's have a look and see if we can find
it oh my god the man has a wall of
ancient debris
i believe it's one there it is okay
finally the cubs base is probably a
candidate for hiding secret bases in to
be honest because it is enormous
and there are so many places to hide but
check this out there is a corner of cubs
pyramid that has a really nice pattern
on it look at that it's a proper mosaic
and he's used the glazed terracotta
really really well here and this
very much inspired me to try and do well
not obviously not the same pattern but i
never use glazed terracotta i find it
quite a difficult block to work with
but i feel like
cubs done such a good job here and i'd
be a fool not to try so i mean massive
shout out to the work done here because
i i really like this so let's go back to
the base and start working on that
interior how do i get out of here
you really gotta respect
the bold choice of blocks lapis lazuli
blocks as the ceiling come on kerb this
is you just you're just showing off and
i've gone the wrong way again
while we're passing by a bit of an
update on button 2.0 still don't know
what this is but other people have been
saying it's the hermitcraft bumbo
bagging society so i mean that that
seems like a bit of a stretch mumbo that
button 2.0 is something to do with
hobbits but i was a hobbit
i don't know if i'm going to get
involved with well i've signed up so i
am involved but there's an update you
know the the clock is ticking we we're
nearly halfway very much nearly halfway
okay so diamond chandelier
glazed terracotta floor
that's the plan and that's what i want
to achieve at the start of today's
episode so let's just get into it time
lapse style
[Music]
there it is
the floor of the mansion or at least
part of the floor of the mansion i used
this really nice bright red which i
didn't really expect but it ended up
being the complementary color
for the warped stem over there and i
know that it was probably designed this
way for the for the nether update but i
never really considered it i just you
know kind of just thought this would
match and it did along with the glazed
terracotta i really went out of my
comfort zone here and i think it paid
off but i think for me the highlight
isn't the floor i'm more proud of the
floor but the highlight is the diamond
chandelier it is really really bright
and sparkly i'm pretty proud of how this
has ended up being so you're gonna have
to let me know what you think but i
don't know i don't think i'm gonna
change any of this because i'm i'm
really feeling it so while i was
building this over the course of a few
hours while i was making it this thing
has been working away making more melons
and pumpkins which has been supplying my
villager trading hall down here so we're
gonna oh
sorry i just barged in on your little
i'm stuck in here with you forever okay
there we go so let's see how much it's
been producing yep
that is a lot better so the base is
finally being a bit more productive
which is excellent so now that the main
hall is pretty much where i want it to
be maybe there's a few bits of detail
that i'll add later on i mean i added
some signs and such for a little extra
detail but this room
pretty much where i want it to be now
so now i need to focus on the wings now
again this is a project that i'm slowly
going to do bit by bit but i have
already made some progress over here so
my plan for this wing of the mansion is
going to be a brand new villager breeder
and it's actually going to be an
automatic one that i can turn on and
turn off so i'm not constantly throwing
bread at them so i've got this all set
up now i just need to move the villagers
all the way up and in here before we
start moving these and you guys know
moving villagers worst
so these are the only two villagers i
have left okay so if anything happens to
these guys
it's game over i'm gonna i'm gonna rage
quit hermit craft they just looked at
each other like
they just looked at each other like oh
no
something something terrible is going to
happen
so the main thing the advice that i want
to give you is if you're moving your
villagers around
just double check the tracks and make
sure there's nothing
obvious that's going to go wrong in
theory they're going to go right up here
and just flop straight into there so
i can't see anything going wrong there
should be enough power to get them there
yeah let's just let's just do it i have
a bit more experience with the villagers
now so
let's see how we get on one at a time is
also a really good idea we'll get both
of them on the track and out of here now
another tip for you guys if you're ever
moving villagers glass glass won't make
them suffocate oh i said one at a time
but they've totally gone off without me
what did that just happen the bunch of
green particles well it's not exactly
what i was intending but
that works now you just got to carefully
get rid of the mine cart
come on
yes
yes yes yes
it worked
oh man it worked now that they're here i
need to get these guys to make
another villager really quick because i
need to make this automatic we need a
farmer that's going to take lots of
carrots and feed these guys that's how
that's how this works and there'll be a
link to the design that i've used in the
description as well so in theory the
villagers should come up to them
and throw
carrots i believe last time i was trying
to get these guys to breed they just
wouldn't no no something went wrong
angry angry angry angry okay
i should have done this a long time ago
come on guys
no villagers
oh they're the west
what this doesn't make any sense
maybe
yes
okay wicked that's exactly what we need
but that looks like that they could
easily walk out of there so i'm going to
forestall this and make sure that
there's a barrier because if these
villagers escape they're going to
certainly fall to their death
something's still going wrong here and
it's something i will have to kind of
come back to but
at least i've got what i needed
to get this thing underway so
that's where i'm going to leave this
project for now we're going to come back
to this in the next episode and
hopefully make some decent progress
on making this thing
actually function i need to work out
what's going wrong with the glass
there's always like seriously these
things are so annoying
that one block of glass out of place and
the whole thing doesn't work so
yeah i
it's so annoying but i will figure this
out
but uh it's not something that
i feel like i need to go over a million
times
so i think we're kind of done with the
interior for today's episode i can't get
over like i'm really happy with how this
is sort of filled out and filled in i
mean what do you think of my diamond
chandelier oh this is really funny by
the way i was gonna use this this
diamond chandelier to flex on my wealth
but
the
the diamonds used in this chandelier
they don't even make a dent here's my
diamond box
it took away maybe 20 diamond blocks it
i need to find a better way
to display these diamonds because
keeping them in this shulker box
is not doing it for me so um i'll have
to figure that out at some point but
enough of my base for now
we need to go
to someone else's base man the mansion
is so cool we're gonna head over to
corrales base and if you remember last
episode i
joined in a little bit of a pact of some
kind with b-dubs and impulse
and we decided that we were gonna make
secret bases
in corrales's city
and i've done a little bit of
reconnaissance and i've found the place
that i want to make
my base unfortunately
i can't show you exactly where that is
because like always
can't trust you
just just can't trust you that much
so
i'm gonna have to make this secret room
off camera really quick and then cut to
it i'm just gonna i'm gonna get this
secret room made
and then i'll i'll just i'll magically
appear inside it
guys
i think i figured out
how to flex
on my diamonds
i have come to the conclusion that
making a secret base
is pretty dangerous
and so there's no point making some
pretty interior because it's probably
gonna get found pretty quickly so i
thought i'm just gonna make an ugly
diamond room
just to really rub it in
i i don't know what possessed me to do
this there's something beautifully ugly
about this
so this is my secret base i've not i've
not showed you where it is but i have
got a pesky bird here with me i think
this is the staple of a good secret base
and guess what i mean this has genuinely
made a dent
in my diamond
stocks
uh this is about half of my diamonds
here
and i have actually linked it up because
i have a plan okay and i'm about to take
you through the plan so i've i've linked
this up and there's a little tunnel here
and there boom
this is going to be
the sewer system underneath corrales
base that's right so the plan is i have
no idea where the other guys have made
their base in this city but i thought
we could link them up with a big
sewer system
so obviously that's going to take a
little bit of time
and i need to coordinate with the other
guys now every now and again every time
i do something on the server
basically people say
ah
green's starting another war not not
everything i do has to start a war okay
sometimes i just want to start a society
of sewer related mole people and that's
what we're doing and i figured that this
will be much more fun
if i get more people involved so sitting
at corrales base so sitting in corrales
desk i'm gonna write myself a couple of
invitations for
a couple of my neighbors and see if they
want to just jump in on this thing and
get going also i wonder if corrales will
notice
something like this so yeah i think that
i'm done starting wars and i'm going to
make more
societies of hidden bases mole people
you are cordially invited to make a
secret base in corrales city and join
the sewer society of hermits you can
build anywhere just keep it a secret
from corrales link up your secret base
to the sewers okay the sewers don't
exist yet but there's there's plenty of
time for that let's make a couple copies
as i'm flying around i can't stop
thinking about if i've spelt cordially
right i say
sometimes i say words but i never spell
them and now i'm just i'm just guessing
and now i feel really weird about it i
don't know just
weird things so the first person that
we're going to invite to the sewer
society of hermits is probably
the most suitable candidate the king of
shenanigans etho
himself i
haven't seen him in a while but
where do you leave mail for for ether
you know what this is the spot boom an
invitation we'll see we'll see if he
bites of course these invitations are
just open they don't have to they can
always turn them down but we've already
got three people
potentially living in
corrales city and i've got some really
funny ideas on how to make this even
bigger but in order to make this bigger
i need a few more people not everyone
it'd be madness if we had everyone
living in corrales's city
but enough people right now the next
person i want to invite
is good times with scar we're usually on
the other side of storylines most of the
time
but this time we're going to be secret
base bros well
if he joins
or are we
can't leave baby yoda lying around
maybe i should just move maybe i should
just move baby odor make make it make
make scar think
that he's been stolen when he really has
just moved the last person is actually
ren who has been my neighbor for quite a
while now but i haven't actually done an
awful lot with again this is somewhere i
don't really know where to leave mail
i'm guessing here so the invitations are
set we've got our secret base set up and
we have spent a lot of diamonds getting
things done today
this could end up being quite a lot of
fun to be honest with you i don't i
don't know exactly where this is gonna
go i also heard that shade ees is back
open and shady ease is a floating
shulker box shop
that you can't see unless of course you
load it in
but i
i don't know where it is how do you have
to get really close i guess you have to
find it first
i'm also guessing it would leave a
shadow
maybe it hasn't maybe etho just said
shady ease is open
but he hasn't actually built anything
because look you see that that shadow
that tells me that shulker box is there
shop made of shulker boxes is no good if
you can't find it
okay i've i've definitely missed
something i have no idea where it is
speaking of shops i have definitely been
putting off this plot over here for a
while i want to do another barge
expansion but i've been
so
busy obviously january is a bit more of
a slow month anyway i like to take a
little more time between episodes
but like i've been doing the interior
and the secret base thing and i haven't
had enough time oh my goodness
oh my goodness i haven't actually taken
any profit from impulse i've been just
giving him the diamonds i haven't
actually done anything to make
you know an impulse worthy area or
anything like that i have a really big
project in mind for the barge the next
expansion will be magnificent the issue
is the time thing so there's going to be
a little patience involved on on your
guys's side in order to get this uh done
because i need to plan that out i'm back
in the sewers and i'm just trying to
figure out a design for this now i've
got very limited resources down here and
you know leaving leaving the sewers and
coming back is a bit of a pain so what i
was thinking of doing was just trying to
kind of nail a sort of
blank canvas kind of style
and i don't think it's going too well we
do have that sort of sewer shape
but you know if everyone on this
corrales hiding game the sewer society
whatever we're calling this thing
then we're gonna need to nail this
design and make sure that it's
consistent so i'm not completely sold on
this i may need to get some help however
i think we're under something pretty
good
all of the little details can come way
later i one thing for sure is that i
really do want to have water but not
enough water that it's annoying just
like just a you know a little bit like
this
and if you want a little bit of extra
detail you can of course put some oh
i s oh it's p dubs
oh it's b dubs okay we're good
i thought corrales was online for a
second there we're okay
we're okay
all right i'm glad that someone's
actually making some progress elsewhere
so i think we have an idea of where b
dubs is uh but look check it out all i
wanted to do is have some like dripping
water going down here so what i want to
do is just kind of off camera i'm gonna
kind of nail this design i'll talk to
everyone about what we're gonna
i still don't know how i've been playing
this game for 10 years and i still don't
know how water works but as you can see
i'm gonna have to make a couple of trips
back and forth with some fresh stone i'm
gonna need some cracked bricks i'm also
going to need some mossy bricks and you
get the idea i'm gonna need a lot of
blocks to make this work but
i'm just not quite happy with this so
i'm gonna need some some assistance from
the rest of the guys and probably make
it look overgrown and if i had some
slime i reckon some slime coming out of
the walls and stuff make it look a bit
gross like i mean this is a sewer this
is not gonna look particularly clean
i'm a little bit concerned
that b-dubs is really close to my secret
base let's just let me just check he has
you know oh
oh i'm stuck in here let's just check
that b-dubs isn't actually in our base
he might just be extremely close
okay he's extremely close uh i no he's
he's found it
he's uh
yeah
uh
i'm gonna need a new secret base by the
time that anyone sees this video this
diamond box is gone
come on in let me show you around
i guess that's the problem you want to
see how close i am to corrales i haven't
even seen corrales i've been rumbled
maybe i can leave this up for a little
while
he nearly got he nearly got got there ha
ha
okay so i i need i need help with this
sewer
well i guess the bird's out of the bag
there well that grates my cheese i just
made an entire episode based around this
secret base and it's been rumbled
instantly
look look how close i am to corrales
office like i'm literally right here
by the time that corrales gets here
though i'll be gone
so
say goodbye pesky bird we need to i mean
this is the beauty of the diamond box we
can move it around super easily but i'm
afraid that is all we have time for
today we've been rumbled instantly the
plan is still is in place secret bases
link them up with a sewer
i'm gonna go and work on that off camera
to make sure that they are hidden
a little better this time good bye
you